Michel Moraes

Senior Full-stack Web Developer

- Plaza Campo da Torre 38, 3D Pontevedra 36002 Spain
- +34 679119468
- github.com/michelmany
- michel@nitdesign.com.br
- in linkedin.com/in/michelmany



About

I am Brazilian from Rio de Janeiro, resident in Spain since 2017, I am 35 years old and I have worked as a Graphic Designer and Web Developer since 2004 across a variety of roles and different companies.

I started my career when I was still at school. Since that time, I have been improving my skills doing several courses and studying hard by myself. Due to that, I have been building strong skills in website development. Over the years I have been providing website development with a creative services. Also, I have been dealing with optimization (SEO) and web hosting websites, blogs, portal and anything else related to information technology on the Internet.

My double degrees, "Graphic Design" and "Webdesign and Interfaces", allowed me to get both sides of view: Design and Code. These concepts afford me to develop abilities for both roles Front End and Back End.

Nowadays, my main strengths are HTML, CSS and Javascript, Vue.js and React for the Front End role and PHP, Laravel Framework and WordPress for the Back End role, and also my natural instinct for design. However, my horizon is beyond what I do. In other words, I frequently learn about new codes, trend and conceptions, therefor, I have studied some tools in order to be aware what is the latest technological advances.

 ${\rm I}$ am passionate about what ${\rm I}$ do because ${\rm I}$ believe that work and fun go together.

Education

University: Universidade Estácio de Sá (Brazil) | 2005 - 2009

Degree: Bachelor Degree of Graphic Design

University: Instituto INFNET (Brazil) | 2009 - 2012 Degree: Webdesign and Interfaces - WebMaster

Skills

Front End Role

HTML5/CSS (SASS), Javascript ES6+ (inc. Ajax, JSON, jQuery)
 Vue.js + Vuex / React.js + Redux.

Back End Role

- PHP OO, NodeJS, MySQL, MongoDB.
- Git, Github, Bitbucket

Frameworks/CMS:

• Laravel, Vue.js, Wordpress, Umbraco, Bootstrap.

Build Tools and DevOps:

•Webpack, Gulp, Docker, CI/CD, Apache, Nginx, AWS, DigitalOcean.

Version Control

• Git, GitHub, GitLab, BitBucket.

Employment history

Employer: Simplicity Partners (London/UK)

Duration: July 2016 - March 2020

Role: Full Stack Web Developer (Remote Full-time)

Description:

A full-time job dealing with creation and maintenance websites providing front-end and back-end skills. In addition, giving solution and advice about the latest technologies.

Responsibilities:

- Implementing website interface layers Bootstrap, CSS3/Sass, Javascript/jQuery/Vue.js, PHP CMS WordPress, C#/Razor with Umbraco CMS.
- Dealing with WordPress creating custom themes from scratch and Gutenberg Blocks with React and ACF Plugin.
- Dealing with Umbraco CMS making the website editable in the CMS.
- · Building web systems structures.
- Writing systems using PHP language.
- MySQL database modelling and management.
- Creating and supporting backends functions.
- · System validation.

Some projects that I created and participated:

https://www.ldc.com

https://www.draughtmaster.com https://www.carlsberg.com/en-gb/

https://qbeeurope.com

https://qbeeurope.com/unpredictability

https://simplicitypartners.co.uk https://www.smithsdetection.com https://intradco-global.com

Employer: NITDESIGN Creative Studio (Brazil)
Duration: January 2010 - August 2017
Role: Full Stack Web Developer (Owner)

Description:

A full-time job dealing with creation and maintenance websites providing front and back-end skills. In addition, giving solution and advice about the latest technologies.

Responsibilities:

- Creating website interface using Photoshop.
- HTML emails / Newsletter based on MailChimp.
- Implementing website interface layers using HTML, Boostratp, CSS3 and JavaScript/jQuery/AJAX, AngujarJS, Laravel, Git, etc.
- Dealing with WordPress creating themes from scratch.
- Building web systems structures.
- Writing systems using PHP language.
- MySQL database modelling and management.
- Creating and supporting backends functions.
- · System validation.
- Design, coding and development.

Employer: Quatro em Um Comunicação (Brazil) Duration: January 2008 - December 2008 Role: Graphic Designer / Web Designer

Description:

I was within a team of ten members. My mission was to create web and TV interfaces and print materias such as business cards, brochures and banners.

Responsibilities:

- Creating websites and TV layouts using Photoshop.
- Implementing websites interfaces layers using HTML and CSS.
- Creating print material such as business cards, brochures, folders, banners and more.